# Bibhu De

🕈 Delhi, West Bengal, India 🗷 bibhude2@gmail.com 🔲 +919614544971 🛅 in/bibhu-de 🕳 portfolio-bibhude.netlify.app/

### **SUMMARY**

Software Developer with 1 year of experience in full-stack development (MERN, PHP, MySQL), reducing deployment times by 20% and boosting traffic by 40% through efficient solutions and SEO optimization. Skilled in React, Tailwind, and REST APIs.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Full Stack Developer**

**Knowledge Nation Law Centre** 

December 2023 - Present, Hauz Khas, Delhi, 110059

- · Engineered end-to-end digital solutions using MERN stack, PHP, and MySQL, reducing deployment times by 20%.
- Adeptly utilized phpMyAdmin to sculpt and manage robust back-end infrastructures. I implemented PHPMailer to ensure flawless communication within dynamic web applications.
- Executed code improvements by implementing SEO optimization techniques to enhance digital visibility and user accessibility, resulting in a 40% increase in organic traffic using React.js and Node.js.

#### React Js Developer

Shivila Technology PVT LTD

August 2023 - December 2023, Kolkata, WestBengal

- Led development on various projects, including e-commerce platforms, matrimonial websites, rental management systems, and admin dashboards.
- · Achieving 30% faster load times and increasing user engagement by 20% through responsive design and optimized frontend performance.
- Engineered robust, scalable web applications using React-Redux with seamless API integration, improving backend communication by 25% and reducing errors in data handling by 15%, resulting in enhanced user experience and system reliability.

### **PROJECTS**

### **Education marketing Blog With Dynamic Content And admin Pannel**

Client Best Requirement • www.theeducationpress.com/ • July 2024 - August 2024

- Implemented SEO best practices to enhance organic traffic by 40% also, Integrated Tailwind CSS and Bootstrap and FlowBite elements in React.js with Redux dataflow to create responsive UI/UX, achieving a 30% improvement in mobile device load times.
- Developed a backend system using Node.js with Express, MongoDB for database management, and Firebase for image storage with compression.
- REST APIs for efficient client-server, and OAuth2 Google login for secure authentication. Deployed on VPS server using SSH for remote management.

### **Company Websites**

Build for Knowledge Nation for enhance business and development. • knowledgenation.co.in/ • December 2023 - June 2024

- Architected and deployed the complete 'knowledgenation.co.in' and 'firstias.co.in' websites using Bootstrap and CSS, enhancing the usability and aesthetics resulting in a 25% boost.
- Implemented backend functionality using PHP and MySQL, and dynamic content management also Utilized CSS minification and asynchronous loading of JavaScript resources enhancing user engagement by 20%.
- For BLog Sites(bestcoachingindelhi, theeducationmarket ) Implemented SEO best practices using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to enhance search visibility and organic traffic by 40% and also to optimize existing WordPress themes for mobile responsiveness, contributing to a 40% improvement.

#### **SKILLS**

FULL Stack: Frontend: Reactjs, React-Redux, Redux-Toolkit, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Flow Byte. Database: SQL, MYSQL, MongoDB. BACKEND: Node Js, Express, PHP, Ajax, Jquery, Git, Git-Version-Controle, MVC, Restful API, JSON, Apache, Linux, VPS Hosting, Cloud Hosting. Aso Languages: Java, Python, Javascript

#### **EDUCATION**

### MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (MCA)

Minor in Computer Application • Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi • Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh • 2023 • 7.65

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS (HONS)

Minor in MATHEMATICS • The University of Burdwan, West Bengal • Burdwan, West Bengal • 2020 • 6.90

#### **COURSEWORK**

## **Data Science for Engineers**

IIT Madras • 2023 • Python

· Help to build my Minor Project

# CERTIFICATIONS

### Problem Solving(Intermediate)

HackerRank • 2023

 $\cdot$  Certify my Problem Solving Skill